Vishal Kapoor

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

mailwekay@gmail.com

(+91) 8010971828

linkedin.com/in/itsvkapoor

https://www.behance.net/mailwekay568a

Summary

I'm called an artist with many colors in my expertise like designing, motion graphics, web designing and developing of more than 8 years and still experiencing new things and trends to evolve accordingly. I enjoy working in all critical conditions. If hired by you I will be responsible to complete the task within the stipulated time frame and with utmost confidence. Outsource me for your project and I promise to bring in the best output.

Experience

Motion Graphic Designer

Sprinklr

Mar 2022 - Present (2 years 3 months)

- Working as a in-house Motion Graphic Designer in one of the leading software enterprise company.
- Managed delivering the best quality output in tight deadlines while working in different kinds of videos like training videos, youtube promotional videos and marketing campaigns.
- Collaborating with different pods (teams), brainstorming with them to create different professional campaigns while showcasing brand identity and its goal.

Learning Artist

Embibe

Mar 2020 - Mar 2022 (2 years 1 month)

- Creating video for the company's in-house Elearning platform.
- · Managing and achieving tight deadlines keeping in mind company's guidelines and standards.
- Being part of the development of the company's in-house Elearning platform, testing and fixing bugs to make it ready to publish.

Creative Associate

BYJU'S

Apr 2019 - Mar 2020 (1 year)

- Creating concepts and animated storyboards for Elearning videos.
- Animating motion graphics and characters for mainstream school subjects like Civics, History, Biology, etc.
- Interacting with the Content team for accurate content communication along with creativity and mentoring interns to match the work standards.



NEUROSENSUM

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019 (3 months)

- Visualizing and creating adverts for the in-house app design.
- Helping in creating the UI and making prototypes for the app using Figma.

Motion Graphic Artist

PitchWorx

Sep 2017 - Jan 2019 (1 year 5 months)

- Visualizing and creating graphics for explainer videos.
- Animating and synchronization of music with videos.
- Taking on call meetings with clients for better understanding of their concept and feedback for further changes in projects.

Senior Flash Animator

Nov 2016 - Sep 2017 (11 months)

- Development of interactive presentations for web pages and concept model with HTML5 environment along with by using Google Web Designer.
- Development of responsive Emailers and websites by using core HTML tables supported by almost all web clients.
- Managing and directing the creative team for the concept ideas of new campaigns according to clients' needs.

Interactive Designer

EKCS

Sep 2015 - Dec 2016 (1 year 4 months)

- Development of animated advertisements on the basis of the description and instructions given by clients by using Adobe Flash.
- Development of interactive adverts with Click through URL or Click to call enabled outputs on HTML5 platform by using Adobe Edge Animate.
- Trafficking of developed interactive adverts by coordinating with clients and Ad production team by using DFP (Double Click for Publishers) by Google.

Education

Maya Academy of Advanced Cinematics

Diploma of Education, Development of Graphics, Web and 2D Animation Apr 2013 - Jun 2014

Kamal Public Senior Secondary School

Business/Commerce, General 2002 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications

Studio Certified in HTML5 (by Google) - Google

Skills

Video Production • Graphic Design • Photoshop • Corel Draw • Illustrator • Premiere • Flash Professional • Dreamweaver • HTML 5 • CSS